「良医」前情回顾
Previously on "The Good Doctor"...
我是你的邻居
I'm your neighbor.
我正在玩「神秘海域」  但没电了
I'm in the middle of "Uncharted," And I'm dead.
能借我几粒七号电池吗
Can I borrow some triple A's?
有点傻吧
It's kind of silly, isn't it?
我是说我们在搞的地下情
Our relationship... that we're hiding it.
杰瑞德  我们没有「情」
We don't have a relationship.
只有「性」
We have sex.
-你迟到了  -不  是公交迟到了
- You're late. - No, the bus was late.
我没做错什么  公交...
I did nothing wrong. The bus...
好吧  这真是太棒了
Yeah. This is gonna work out great.
所以你对他是一视同仁吗
So you're treating him like anybody else?
你知道他今天把多少病人吓得要死吗
You have any idea how many patients he's scared the crap out of today?
那你就教他
So teach him.
我想教给你们两个的是他不属于这里
I'm teaching you both that he doesn't belong.
我听说你不让肖恩打杂  让他回了外科
I hear you got Shaun off scut and back into surgery.
你以为你给他一点权力
You figure you'll give him a little authority,
他肯定会捅出篓子
he'll screw something up.
总之  如果他成功了
Either way, if he succeeds,
我就是支持过他的人
I'm the guy who just backed him.
如果他失败了  我是院长
And if he fails, I'm the president.
你好  我到处都找遍了
Hello. I've looked everywhere.
好了  我来了  我们...
All right, I'm here now. We'll...
我们会一直找  找到它为止
we'll just keep looking until you find it.
家具怎么都在屋子中间
Why is the furniture in the middle of the room?
我知道我打包进来了  还列了单子
I know I packed it. I made a list.
「梅花螺丝刀」
"Star-tip screwdriver."
看  都打勾了
Look, it's checked.
打勾了
It's checked.
你可能把它跟用来打包餐盘的报纸
Maybe you... you threw it out with the newspapers
一起扔掉了
you used to pack the dishes?
我用气泡膜打包的
I packed with bubble wrap.
那样更保险  还能看清里面
It's safer. And you can see through it.
当然了
Of course you did.
肖恩  路边有一家五金店
Shaun, there's a hardware store up the road.
你可以买个新的
You can buy a new one.
我不想要新的螺丝刀
I don't want a new screwdriver!
我只想要我的螺丝刀
I want my screwdriver!
别闹了
Stop it!
现在是...抱歉
It's the middle of the... I'm sorry.
我不该吼你的  我只是...
I just shouldn't have yelled. J-Just...
先歇会儿吧  来坐下
Let's just take a moment. Sit down, please.
我们可以先用这个  好吗
You know what? We can use this for now, okay?
我没法住在这
I can't stay here.
你当然可以
Of course you can.
-没事的  -我没法住在这
- It'll be fine. - I can't stay here.
洗碗机没法烘干
The...dishwasher doesn't dry,
浴室地漏里有别人的头发
the shower drain has someone else's hair in it.
冰箱保鲜格也总是放不好
And the crisper drawer keeps coming off the track?
你之前就是在修理它吧
I assume that's what you were fixing.
我忘了
I forgot.
你当然忘了
Of course you forgot.
可以理解
It's understandable.
你一直忙得火烧屁股
You've been working your ass off.
你累坏了  压力太大
You're exhausted. You're under a lot of stress.
这里有楼层管理员
There's a super in the building.
你可以随时叫他帮忙
You can call him anytime.
列一张需要修理的东西清单就好
Just make a list of the things you need repaired.
晚点再写  肖恩  晚点
Later, Shaun. Later.
晚点  肖恩
Later, Shaun!
先别管了  睡觉去
Leave it now. Go to bed.
36岁  怀孕22周
36 years old, 22 weeks pregnant.
16周做超声时在胚胎尾椎处发现肿瘤
Ultrasound at 16 weeks revealed a tumor on the fetus' tailbone.
孕妇得了抗磷脂综合征
Mom's got antiphospholipid syndrome.
手术风险很大
Makes surgery high risk.
同时增大了妊娠的风险
Also makes pregnancy high risk.
她流产过三次
She's had three miscarriages.
我们需要做超声和核磁共振
We need to do an ultrasound and MRI
确定肿瘤的生长速度
to measure the tumor's growth rate.
公交迟到可解释不了你为何一脸倦意地出现
Late bus doesn't explain why you're showing up tired
你才刚休息了12小时
after you just had 12 hours off.
我们都很累
We're all tired.
刚值了36小时的班
Our last shift was 36 hours.
我没兴趣跟你争论值班安排
I'm not interested in debating the shift schedule with you.
但我很好奇你为什么总替他说话
But I am curious why you always feel the need to defend him.
我们是一个团队
Well, we're all on the same team.
没错
Yes.
但你们都是四分卫
But you're all quarterbacks.
等训练营结束后
And when training camp is over,
只有一人能上场比赛
there's only gonna be one starter.
胚胎的顶臀长度是21.5厘米
The crown-rump length of the fetus is 21.5 centimeters.
肿瘤的直径是
The diameter of the tumor is...
10.6厘米
10.6 centimeters.
有胚胎一半那么大
Half the size of the fetus.
肿瘤变大了
The tumor's grown.
不是恶性肿瘤  但垄断了供血
It's not cancer, but it is monopolizing the blood supply,
导致胚胎心脏弱化
which is weakening the fetus' heart.
很遗憾  但胚胎无法存活到可以生育的阶段
I'm sorry, but there's no chance it would survive long enough to be viable.
最安全的办法就是终止妊娠
The safest course is to terminate the pregnancy.
如果我们要的是「最安全的办法」
If we were interested in the "safest course,"
就不会连续三次来寻求「不同意见」了
we wouldn't be on our third "second opinion."
求你了  梅伦德斯医生
Please, Dr. Melendez,
只要能救我们的孩子  怎么做都行
we want whatever will save our baby.
怀特医生说你之前做过
Dr. Wright told us you've done fetal surgery
摘除这种肿瘤的胚胎手术
to remove this type of tumor before.
摘除肿瘤后  胚胎就健康了
And without the tumor, our baby would be healthy.
你的抗磷脂综合征
Your antiphospholipid syndrome
如果长时间手术会非常危险
makes a long surgery extremely dangerous.
很有可能出现血栓
There's a high chance for blood clots,
结果可能会危及你的性命
which could have fatal consequences for you.
我们愿意冒险一试
We're willing to take that risk.
如果母亲在手术中死亡  救胚胎又有何用
Saving the fetus doesn't do any good if the mother dies in the process.
我已经流产三次了
I've had three miscarriages.
如果再流产  我还不如去死
If I have to go through that again, I might as well be dead.
-芭芭拉  -真的
- Barb. - It's true.
不  不是的
No, it's not.
你是我见过的最坚强的女人
You're the strongest woman I've ever met.
我们会挺过去的
We'll get through this.
会的  到时我们再怀就是
We will. And... and then we'll try again.
可以通过注射普通肝素
We could manage clotting risk pre-operatively
在术前控制住血栓风险
with an infusion of unfractionated heparin.
以后别再当着病患的面拆我的台
Never contradict me in front of a patient again.
我没有
I didn't.
我赞同你的风险评估
I agree with your assessment of the risks.
所以才提出降低风险的办法
I suggested a way we could mitigate them.
别当着病患的面
Not in front of the patient.
现在没当着病患的面
We're not in front of the patient now.
我刚看到过可以监测
I was just reading about a new technique
经食管超声心动图的新技术
for transesophageal echocardiography monitoring.
如果患者出现心脏问题
If there's a cardiac issue,
我们就能提前知道
it would give us an early warning.
给她做好准备  越快越好
Let's get her prepped. ASAP.
{an8\b0\pos(183,215)\fad(500,500)\fn方正黑体_GBK\fs42\c&HFFFFFF&\3c&HBDC0BD&\2c&HFFFFFF&\4c&HBBBEBB&}良     医
{an8\b0\pos(237,125)\fad(500,500)\fn方正黑体_GBK\fs22\c&HFFFFFF&\3c&HBDC0BD&\2c&HFFFFFF&\4c&HBBBEBB&}第一季    第四集
让JL来负责麻醉
I want J.L. on anesthesia.
告诉新生儿护士长
And let the neo-natal nursing supervisor
我想做个全套预演
know that I want to do a full run-through.
该死
Damn it.
怎么
Yes?
我们这边也很忙
Well, we're a little busy up here, too.
好吧  我会派人过去
All right. I'll send someone.
安德鲁斯在急诊顶替利姆
Andrews is covering for Lim in the ER.
他有个患者需要挑疔
He has a patient who needs a boil lanced.
整形医师挑不了疔
A plastic surgeon can't lance a boil?
整形医师可以  但他是外科主任
Plastic surgeons can. Chief surgeons don't.
你和莫菲过去
You and Murphy.
什么
What?
是我们说服了你做胚胎手术
It was our ideas that convinced you to do the fetal surgery,
而你却罚我们去给安德鲁斯干杂活
and now you're punishing us with Andrews' scut work?
不是罚你
You're not getting punished.
是罚他
He is.
今天又迟到了
For being late. Again.
但我不放心让患者和他独自相处
But I don't trust him alone with a patient.
而既然你那么喜欢维护他
And since you like to defend him
看起来也知道如何和他沟通...
and seem to know how to communicate with him...
快去快回
Hurry back.
奥利维亚·哈特曼
Olivia Hartman?
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
我是说  医生
I mean Doctor.
你18岁
You're 18?
没错  女士
Yes, ma'am.
疔在哪
Where's the boil?
在...在下面
It's... It's down there.
下面哪里
Down where?
肖恩  在她阴唇上
Shaun. It's, um, on her labia.
疼吗
Is it painful?
就像把保龄球当棉条塞进去一样疼
Like I used a bowling ball for a tampon.
好吧  疔不应该那么疼的
Okay. Boils shouldn't hurt that much.
我能看看吗
Okay if we take a look?
好
Okay.
往下挪一点
If you just scoot down,
把脚放在蹬子上
put your feet in the stirrups...
很好
Great.
局部肿胀
The swelling is fairly localized.
与表观伤害不符的剧烈痛感
Extreme pain that's out of proportion to the visible injury
你可能感染了坏死性噬肉菌
could mean you have necrotizing flesh-eating bacteria.
什么
What?!
我会在手术前使用肝素
I'm gonna use the heparin pre-operatively
以及经食管超声心动图监测器
and a T.E.E. monitor.
还不够
Still not enough.
已经详细解释了心脏病发作或中风的风险
The risk of a heart attack or stroke was thoroughly explained.
患者仍坚持手术
The patient still wants the surgery.
是她想做  还是你想做
She wants it? Or you want it?
确实
Yes,
挽救胚胎性命可以给我加分
saving a fetus' life would be good news for me.
还有其他问题吗
Any other questions?
或者辱骂
Or insults?
放松  我不是侮辱你
Relax. I'm not insulting you.
你当然想做这个手术
Of course you want to do the surgery.
但如果你做这样的手术
But you do surgeries like this,
患者可能会因此死去
some patients are going to die.
我们部门的手术成功率会降低
And then our department's success rate goes down,
经费随之减少
and then our funding goes down,
你就做不了类似手术了
and then you can't do surgeries like this.
所以如果有什么影响了你的判断...
So if your judgment is clouded in any way, just --
没有
It's not.
好吧
Okay.
抱歉  我知道这很疼
I'm sorry. I know this hurts,
但我得插入窥器  才能给你做检查
but I really do need to insert a speculum for this part of the exam.
如果真的如他所说
If I really have what he says,
你是不是得切掉我的...
does that mean you have to cut off my --
不  我之前说了
No. No, as I said,
脓肿很可能是由未经治疗的衣原体感染所引起的
the abscess is most likely the result of an untreated chlamydia infection.
阴部神经
我们会把脓液排出来
We'll drain the abscess,
阴唇后神经
并给你抗生素治疗
give you antibiotics.
你会没事的
You'll be fine.
抱歉
I'm -- I'm sorry.
巴氏腺囊肿导致坐骨海绵体肌痉挛
The inflamed Bartholin gland is causing the ischiocavernosus muscle
并挤压阴唇神经
to spasm and pinch the labial nerve.
你需要抬高插入的角度
You need to start with a more upward angle.
我能试试吗
Can I try?
还是我来比较好
I think it's better if I do this.
好吧  好吧  你来
Yeah, okay. Fine.
我们可以联系你父母吗  告诉他们...
Can we, uh, call your parents? Let them know --
不
No.
我18岁了  已经成年了
I'm 18. I'm an adult.
成年人也需要精神支持
Even adults need emotional support.
需要有人在手术后送你回家
Someone to drive them home after surgery.
我打车回去
Uh, I'm gonna take a taxi.
我带钱了
I have money.
没什么可不好意思的
There's nothing to be embarrassed about.
四分之一的大学生在毕业前感染过性病
25% of college students contract an STD before graduation.
我没有不好意思
I'm not embarrassed.
我也对性病非常了解
And I know all about STDs.
我每个月都会做检查
I get tested every 30 days.
阴道壁及宫颈无坏死
There's no necrosis on the vaginal wall or cervix.
你已经插进去了
You got it in already?
是的  肯定不是噬肉菌感染
Yes. It's definitely not flesh-eating bacteria.
-我弄错了  -太好了
- I was wrong. - Thank God.
你仍需要手术排净巴氏腺脓肿
You do need surgery to drain the Bartholin gland abscess.
你为什么每个月都做性病检测
Why do you get an STD test every 30 days?
我必须得做  工作原因
I have to. For work.
我拍色情片
I do porn.
脐带长48厘米
The umbilical is 19 inches,
因此我们可以剖腹产取出胚胎
which will allow us to remove the fetus via Caesarean
并让其在我切除肿瘤时躺在母亲腿上
and rest it in its mother's lap while I excise the tumor.
但难的是
Now, the hard part
要在切除肿瘤后把胚胎重新放回母体
will be reinserting the fetus afterwards.
我们不能过度牵拉子宫壁
We can't overstretch the uterine wall,
并且我们得确保每一针都严丝密合
and we must be certain that every suture is tight enough
保证子宫能挺过未来四个多月胚胎的拳打脚踢
to handle four more months of kicks and thrown elbows.
有空谈谈吗
Do you have a minute?
可以等等吗
Can it wait?
不能
No.
我不想做手术
I don't want to do it.
你跟妻子谈过了吗
Have you talked to your wife?
说了  但她现在不理智
Yes, but she's not thinking rationally.
你也听到了  她宁死也不愿失去孩子
You heard her say she'd rather die than lose this baby.
抱歉  但是丈夫无权干涉
I'm sorry, but husbands don't have veto power
妻子的医疗决策
over their wife's medical decisions.
丈夫无权让你停止他妻子的手术
A husband can't stop you from operating on his wife.
但是父亲有权让你停止他孩子的手术
But a father can stop you from operating on his child.
什么类型的色情片啊
What kind of porn?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我一直忙于做检查  看她是否需要手术
I was too busy doing all the labs and imaging she needed for surgery.
忘记问她要简历了
I forgot to ask for her résumé.
我是说  她是真正的演员吗
I just mean, is she an actual actress,
就是剧情相关的人  还是...
like in stuff with a story, or...
现在色情片还有剧情吗
Do they even make porn with stories anymore?
有时候有
Sometimes.
你看毛片
You watch porn?
他为什么不能看
Why wouldn't he?
我不知道  他看起来...
I don't know. He just seems...
他是个男人  所有男人都看毛片
He's a guy. All guys watch porn.
你检查完安德鲁斯的患者了吗
You finished with Andrews' patient?
没有  那不是疖
No. It wasn't a boil.
是巨大的巴氏腺囊肿压迫了她的阴部神经
It's a large Bartholin gland abscess that's pressing on her pudendal nerve.
显然这引起了外科主任的兴趣
Which apparently does interest a chief surgeon.
我们明早会协助安德鲁斯进行手术
We're gonna assist Andrews when he drains it first thing in the morning.
想着和你确认一下
We just thought we'd check with you.
回家睡觉吧
Go home. And sleep.
别玩游戏  或者其他提神的事
Not play video games or whatever it is keeping you up.
我不觉得这是打游戏
I don't think it's video games.
你也回去吧  忙了一天了
You can head out, too. It's been a long day.
-那个... -胚胎手术暂缓
- But what about... - Fetal surgery's been put on hold.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
回家吧
Go home.
胚胎一旦从子宫中拿出
Once the fetus is removed from the uterus,
就可被称为「孩子」了
one could argue that it becomes a child.
太荒谬了
That's ridiculous.
有很多法律先例...
There are numerous legal precedents...
这保证保障了母亲的选择权
That guarantee the mother's right to choose.
她的身体她做主
It's her body. It's her control.
我同意继续做手术
I'm completely comfortable going ahead with this surgery.
我也是
As am I.
我之前反对  现在也坚决不同意
I never was, and I certainly am not now.
抱歉  在我们确认父母意见
I'm sorry. Until we're certain there is no liability
与责任无关之前  我也不同意
connected to parental consent, neither am I.
看来我们取得一致意见的是
Well, the one thing I think we can all agree on
这位母亲无权做任何事
is that the mother has the power to do nothing.
如果她不终止妊娠
And if she doesn't terminate
或者做肿瘤摘除手术
or have the surgery to remove the tumor...
长着巨大肿瘤的胚胎就会死于
A fetus with a massive tumor will die...
有抗磷脂综合征的患者腹中
inside a patient with APS.
这位母亲也会死的  对吧
Then the mother would die, too, right?
如果我们什么都不做  他们都会死
So we do nothing, and they both die.
或者我们做一些既合法又道德完备的事
Or we can do something that's legally and ethically complicated,
也许他们都能活
and maybe they both live.
董事会已批准手术
The board has approved the surgery.
谢谢
Thank you.
-芭芭拉... -马克  别说了
- Barb, please... - Mark, stop.
-如果你爱我  -不
- If you loved me... - No.
-不  别这么说  -不  真的
- No, do not say that. - No, it's true.
如果你真的爱我
If you really loved me...
正因为我爱你  我才想保护你
I'm trying to protect you because I love you.
我不需要你的保护
I don't need your protection.
我需要你支持我
I need your support.
明早我们会为你准备手术
We'll start prepping you first thing in the morning.
试着睡会儿吧
Try and get some sleep.
谢谢
Thank you.
我还是不能相信
I still can't believe it.
那个18岁的大学生拍毛片
That 18-year-old college students do porn?
她不是那种人
She's just not the type.
你怎么知道她是哪种人  你刚认识她
How do you know what "type" she is? You just met her.
做了个病史和盆腔检查而已
Did one medical history and pelvic exam.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
别  说啊
No, go ahead.
告诉我为什么错了
Tell me all the reasons why I'm wrong.
我高中时  在出走青少年庇护所当过志愿者
I volunteered at a shelter for runaway teens when I was at high school.
认识了很多性工作者
Got to know a lot of sex workers.
他们各不相同  但都有一样的...
They're not all the same, but they do have the same...
「盔甲」
armor.
我不信
I don't believe it.
-你觉得我在说谎  -不是
- You think I'm lying? - No.
不  我觉得你对我敞开心扉了
No, I think you just opened up to me,
开始分享一些私事
actually shared something personal.
高中的社会服务而已  没什么大不了的
It was high-school community service. It's not a big deal.
不  这很重要  非常重要
Oh, no, it's a big deal. This is huge.
-就像我在剥洋葱  -闭嘴
- I am peeling the onion. - Shut up.
其实更像是用大钝砍刀砍椰子  但...
Actually, it's more like hacking through a coconut with a dull machete, but...
「钝」就对了  非常钝
"Dull" is right. Very dull.
感觉不错  不是吗
It feels good, doesn't it?
你应该经常这样
You should do it more often.
你还是别担心我不会做的事情
How about you stop worrying about what I won't do
转而享受一下我将要做的事情吧
and just enjoy what I will?
你觉得她心智健全吗
Do you think she's of sound mind?
你现在真的想谈工作吗
You really want to talk about work right now?
她基本上威胁要自杀了
She's basically threatening to commit suicide.
她没要自杀
She's not suicidal.
她只是非常想要个孩子
She's... She's just desperate to have a child.
这也许是她最后的机会
This is probably her last chance.
她可以领养啊
She could adopt.
-那不一样  -是吗
- It's not the same. - Really?
你觉得那没区别吗
You don't think there's a difference?
对  没有
No, I don't.
亲自怀胎九月
Carrying a fetus in your body for nine months.
你觉得那不会建立起特殊的关系吗
You don't think that creates a unique relationship?
我觉得每段关系都有其独特之处
I think every relationship is unique.
对  当然
Yeah, of course.
你想说什么
What are you saying?
我只是觉得这很自私
I just think it's selfish.
我是说  她要经历很多
I mean, for her to go through so much,
也强迫她丈夫克服这些
to put your husband through so much,
只是为了这一段经历
just so you can have a certain experience
更何况还有其他方法
when there are other ways.
确实
Yeah, okay.
但你想要孩子的  对吧
But...you want children, though, right?
我们谈过这个
We've talked about this before.
没错  我想要孩子
Yes, I-I want children.
并且是我们的孩子
But our children.
你怀胎十月生的孩子
Like, from you getting pregnant.
是的
Yes.
但如果这样行不通呢
But what if that doesn't happen?
万一我怀不上孩子
What if I couldn't get pregnant
或者决定不想自己生
or if I decided that I didn't want to?
而想去领养一个
That I wanted to adopt instead?
你有什么事瞒着我吗
Is there something you're not telling me?
确实有
Actually, there is.
当我们一起开会时
When we're in meetings together,
别再说我的想法很荒谬
don't ever call my ideas "ridiculous."
别这样  我认真的
Come on, I'm being serious.
我也是
So am I.
你说得对  我很抱歉
You're right. I'm sorry.
不会再这样了
It won't happen again.
天啊  你吓到我了
Geez, you scared me.
-你在看什么  -没什么
- What're you reading? - Nothing.
-我能看吗  -不能
- Can I read it? - No.
-为什么  -因为
- Why? - Because.
为什么
Why?
因为
Because.
为什么
Why?
因为没有文字
Because there's nothing to read.
只是图片
Just pictures.
你从哪儿弄来的
Where'd you get this?
科琳·迈尔斯
Colleen Myers.
她爸的柜子里有好多
Her dad has so many in his closet,
她拿出几本来她爸都不知道
he doesn't even notice when she takes a few.
她真漂亮
She's pretty.
确实很漂亮
She sure is.
该睡觉了  熄灯
It's bedtime. That means lights out.
我坐过站了
I missed my stop.
I missed my stop!
林伍德广场
Lynwood Place!
我要在林伍德广场下车
I need to get off at Lynwood Place.
我在林伍德广场停的时候
Well, then you should've been paying attention
你就应该注意
when I stopped at Lynwood Place.
下一站就更远了
Next stop's gonna be even further away,
我要是你...
so if I were you...
肖恩
Shaun?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事
Yes.
你在等人吗
Are you waiting for someone?
没有
No.
我的方向感也非常差
I'm horrible at directions, too.
每次我从地铁站出来
Every time I exit a BART station,
走过三条街之后才能意识到
I walk like three blocks before I realize
我走错方向了
I'm going the wrong direction.
你运气很好  我去健身房了
You're lucky I actually made it to the gym.
我喜欢在人少的时候去
I like to go when it's not crowded,
但工作之后就没动力去运动了
but it's so hard to motivate after work.
一半时间我都没...
Half the time I end up not...
你有臭味
You stink.
我知道  我身上有味道
I know. I'm disgusting.
但我不想在那里洗澡
But I can't shower there.
我怕被传染脚气
I'm terrified of foot fungus.
既然我们开始真心话攻击
Hey, you know, as long as we're tossing out truth grenades,
我得说当你的邻居真不爽
you suck at being a neighbor.
首先  你把电池要回去了
First, you take back your batteries,
你还会在半夜把我吵醒
and then you wake me up in the middle of the night
不停跺脚还敲着管子
stomping around and banging on pipes.
那到底是怎么回事
What the hell's up with that?
我的水槽漏水
My sink drips.
我睡不着  所以想修好它
I couldn't sleep, so I tried to fix it.
但我找不到我的螺丝刀  我很焦虑
Then I couldn't find my screwdriver, which made me anxious.
你不让我睡觉就因为你找不到螺丝刀
You kept me up because you were anxious about a screwdriver?
是的  我非常焦虑
Yes. I was very anxious.
你太逗了
You're funny.
我很臭  你很焦虑
I stink. You're anxious.
你总是怎么想就怎么说
You always say exactly what's on your mind.
和大多数人完全相反
It's the total opposite of most guys.
这很好
It's nice.
晚安
Good night.
今晚别再修水龙头了
And don't go fixing any faucets tonight.
那是工人的工作
That's Armen's job.
这是我公寓需要修理的物品清单
This is a list of repairs I need for my apartment.
33号公寓
Number 33.
你有什么毛病
What the hell is your problem?
抱歉  你好
Sorry. Hello.
我叫肖恩·莫菲  很高兴见到你
My name is Shaun Murphy. It's very nice to meet you.
在半夜12:40见到你我一点都不高兴
No, it's not nice to meet me at 12:40 a.m.
是的
Yes.
格拉斯曼医生说我需要修东西的话可以随时找你
Dr. Glassman said I can call you any time I need something fixed.
格拉斯曼医生是谁
Who the hell is Dr. Glassman?
他是圣何塞圣文德医院的院长
He's the president at San Jose St. Bonaventure Hospital.
我是那里的外科住院医师
I'm a surgical resident there.
我不管你是圣文德本人还是谁
Well, I don't care if you're St. Bonaventure himself.
除非有火灾或洪水
Unless it's a fire or flood,
不然我只在九点到五点间工作
I only work 9:00 to 5:00.
我...
I'll...
明天再在你工作时间过来
try and come back tomorrow between those times.
你都把我吵醒了  就把单子给我吧
You already woke me up. Just give me the damn list.
是我的错
It's my fault.
我应该想到你会按字面意思理解我的话
I should've known you would take what I said literally.
没事
It's okay.
你知道吗  肖恩
Actually, you know what, Shaun?
这不是我的错
It's not my fault.
这是你的问题  你很聪明
It's your responsibility. You're smart.
你应该运用自己的常识
You should be able to use your common sense.
去理解别人的话
When somebody says something,
你应该弄清楚他们真正的意思
you should figure out what they really mean.
当事情进展和你预想的不同时
And when things don't go exactly how you expected them,
换个角度
navigate that.
有一种职业叫私人护理
There's a thing called a Personal Support Worker.
可以想成家庭健康护理
Think of it like a home health aide.
我不需要  谢谢
No, thank you.
我能照顾好自己
I can take care of myself.
每个人都或多或少需要帮助
Everybody needs a little help now and then.
我在考虑让他们给我派一个
I-I'm thinking of asking them to give me one.
我自己生活很久了
I've lived by myself a long time.
在怀俄明州的卡斯珀
In Casper, Wyoming.
在卡斯珀大家会照顾你
Everybody looked out for you in Casper.
在卡斯珀大家都会互相留意
Everybody looks out for everybody in Casper.
这里是圣何塞  大城市
This is San Jose. It's a big city.
对住所的要求可比医疗需求大得多
And residency is a whole lot more demanding than medical --
我不需要助手
I don't need an aide.
我们只是聊聊  肖恩
We're just talking, Shaun.
-我不需要助手  -好吧
- I don't need an aide! - Okay, okay.
-好的  -好吧
- Okay. - Okay.
好的
Okay.
改天再说吧
We'll table it for some other time.
好好吃早餐  好吗
Let's enjoy our breakfast, okay?
艾伦先生
Mr. Allen?
我想劝她救救自己
I'm trying to convince her to save herself.
我不想拿妻子的命冒险
I don't want to roll the dice with my wife's life.
但她愿意
But she does.
我们要开始帮她做准备了
We're gonna start prepping her now,
几小时后她就要进手术室
and she goes into the O.R. in a few hours.
我明白她为何如此迫切
I understand why she's desperate.
但不明白你为何如此
But not why you are.
如果她死了  责任在你
If she dies, it's your fault.
如果她活下来呢
And what if she lives?
你就拥有了需要你的妻子和孩子
You're gonna have a wife and child who need you,
而你却一直想把她赶出你的生活
and you keep driving her out of your life.
我不是迫切
I'm not desperate.
我很有信心
I'm confident.
你应该感到好受点
Which should make you feel better.
拉钩
Retraction.
我来切口
I'll make the incision,
然后由你插入导管
and then I want you to insert the Word catheter.
盆腔检查做的很棒  莫菲医生
Good job on the pelvic exam, Dr. Murphy.
患者还有肿胀  肯定不简单
With all this swelling, it couldn't have been easy.
谢谢
Thank you.
你怎么知道是谁
How do you know who...
我自有渠道
Oh, I have my ways.
就像圣诞老人
Like Santa.
我告诉的他
I told him.
没有礼物给你
No presents for you.
插入导管
Insert the drain.
但我很好奇
But I'm curious.
一个甚至都不能跟同事握手的人
How could a guy who can't even shake a co-worker's hand
是怎么克服障碍做盆腔检查的
be comfortable doing a pelvic exam?
握手是因为太用力  会疼
People squeeze too hard. It hurts.
送到实验室培养
Send this to the lab for culture.
那我猜你也不太喜欢拥抱吧
So, I'm guessing you're not that into hugs.
我不喜欢受到压迫
I don't like to be squeezed.
那如果是你喜欢的人呢
Well, what if it's somebody you like?
你爱的人呢
Or somebody you love?
你谈过女朋友吗
Have you ever had a girlfriend?
曾经  差点吻一个女孩
I almost kissed a girl. Once.
你知道俗话说得好
Well, you know what they say --
如果第一次不成功
If at first you don't succeed...
你是想嘲弄我还是鼓励我
Are you trying to mock me or encourage me?
我在尝试着了解你
I'm trying to get to know you
以便了解嘲弄你和鼓励你的时机
so I know when I should mock and when I should encourage.
何时是嘲弄你的时机
When's the right time to mock you?
再用力点按压脓肿
Press harder on that abscess.
现在脓液应该排净了
It should have drained by now.
不太对劲
Something's wrong.
脓已经排出  但肿胀并未消除
The gland's evacuated, but the swelling's not going down.
心率和血压正常
Heart rate and BP are stable.
能再亮点吗
Can I get a little more light, please?
-该死  -怎么了
- Damn. - What is it?
肿胀没有消除是因为脓肿下有肿瘤
The swelling isn't going down because there's a mass beneath the abscess.
不只是压迫着外阴神经
And it's not just pressing on the pudendal nerve --
已经完全包围了
It's totally engulfed it.
情况很糟
That's bad.
非常糟糕
Very bad.
已经做完了吗
You're done already?
我们已经设法排净脓肿
We were able to drain the abscess.
我已经觉得好多了
I already feel better.
这只是止痛药的效果
That's only because of the pain meds.
之所以痛感非常强烈
The reason the pain was so severe
是因为这并非只是脓肿
was because it wasn't just an abscess.
下面长了一个会阴肌瘤
There's perineal myoma underneath.
那是什么
What's that?
是一种纤维瘤
A fibroid tumor.
没有癌变  但是它包围了神经
It's not cancerous, but it is wrapped around the nerve.
我们得切除肿瘤
We need to remove the tumor,
但这样必须切除神经
but to do that, we will have to sever the nerve.
你的生殖器官会失去所有感觉
You'll lose all feeling in your genitals.
非常遗憾
I'm so sorry.
我就知道
I knew it.
是上帝在惩罚我
God's punishing me.
不  绝非如此
No, absolutely not.
这只是随机生长的...
This is just a random growth...
你信教吗
You're religious?
是的
Yes.
至少以前信
Or at least I used to be.
很久未感念过上帝了
I haven't thought about God in a really long time.
但生病住院后...
But being in here...
你确定不要我们帮你联络父母吗
You sure you don't want us to call your parents?
不  我没办法面对他们的脸
No. I couldn't bear to see the look on their faces.
尤其是爸爸
Especially my dad's.
父母就是如此  为你分忧
Well, that's what parents are for.
让你不必自己承担一切
So you don't have to do these things alone.
你能告诉你父亲你是个妓女吗
Could you tell your father you're a whore?
你是犯过错  但那都过去了
You made a mistake. That is all.
-患者生命体征  -稳定
- Patient vitals? - Stable.
-胚胎呢  -稳定
- Fetus? - Stable.
很好
Okay.
准备好了吗
Is everybody ready?
手术刀
Knife.
拉钩
Retractor.
好的
Okay.
切入子宫
Cutting into the uterus.
经食管超声心动图显示前壁机能减退
T.E.E. is showing anterior wall hypokinesis.
收缩压90  给我漂浮导管
Systolic pressure 90. Get me a Swan.
静脉注射功能降低  她心脏病突发了
I.V. function is decreasing. She's having a heart attack.
马上缝合切口
I need you to close the incision.
-马上  持针器  -快去拿荧光镜
- On it. Needle driver. - Get a fluoroscope in here!
我要对她进行球囊反搏
I'm gonna prep her for a balloon pump.
芭芭拉
Barbara?
手术时产生了并发症
There was a complication during surgery.
血块堵塞了你的心脏动脉
A blood clot blocked an artery in your heart.
我们及时处理了
We were able to catch it in time.
我的孩子呢
And my baby?
胚胎稳定
The fetus is stable.
我们打开子宫前  你心肌梗塞了
The M.I. happened before we opened the uterus.
这么说  我们又回到原点了吗
So, we're right back where we started?
你刚刚心脏病发作
You just had a heart attack.
我不在乎
I don't care.
现在没有选择了
There is no other option now.
如果不结束妊娠  胚胎会死在子宫内
If we don't terminate and the fetus dies in utero,
产生的血块会击垮你的心脏和大脑
the resulting clots will overwhelm your heart and brain.
所以我们更要再试一次
Which is exactly why we need to try again.
你在说什么
What're you talking about?
你得切除肿瘤
You need to remove the tumor.
你之前求我别做手术
You begged me not to do the surgery before.
之前我以为我能说服她
I thought I could talk her out of it then.
现在我知道我不能
Now I know I can't.
你要是不做  她就会死
Either you do it, or she dies.
此前  如果我们被起诉
Before, if we got sued,
他们至少有个人站在我们这边
we'd at least have one of them on our side,
但现在  他们达成一致了
but now, with them both aligned --
他们能起诉我们不动手术吗
Can they sue us for not operating?
他们可以争辩我们放弃治疗
They could argue that we abandoned care.
我们还在提供治疗
We're still offering care.
只不过不是他们想要的治疗
Just not the care that they want.
这都怪你
Which is your fault.
如果你一开始没给她希望
If you hadn't offered her hope to begin with,
也许我们还能说服她
we might have been able to reason with her.
切口周围有多疼痛
How's the pain around the incision?
满级十级的话  五级疼痛
5 out of 10.
我会加大剂量
I'll up the dosage.
心绞痛吗
Any chest pain?
没有  心脏感觉很好
No. My heart actually feels fine.
好的
Good.
如果她不想结束妊娠  我们也无能为力
If she doesn't want to terminate, there's nothing we can do.
我们就送她回家等死吗
So we just send her home to die?
那是她的决定
It is her decision.
我们可以告诉她我们进行胚胎手术
We could tell her we were going ahead with the fetal surgery.
但等她被麻醉...
But once she's under --
我就当作你没说过这句话
I'm gonna pretend you never said that.
如果那是救她的唯一机会
If it's the only chance to save her life --
这正是我想说的
This is exactly what I'm talking about.
你不会骗要自杀的人来阻止他跳楼吗
You wouldn't lie to convince a suicidal person to climb down off the ledge?
故意隐瞒患者一场重大外科手术
Knowingly lying to a patient about a major medical surgery --
好了  够了
Okay, okay! Hey!
欺骗患者是一回事
Lying to a patient is one thing.
未经他们同意而进行手术
Performing surgery without their consent --
是缺乏职业道德并且违法的
It's unethical and illegal.
还很疯狂
And insane.
我只是...
I just...
我不想这么做
I don't want to do this.
我们还有其他选择
It's not our only option.
你要我再尝试做胚胎手术吗
You want me to attempt the fetal surgery again?
如果只有这个办法能救她
If it's the only way to save her life.
第一次的话  只有这个办法能救她
The first time, it was the only way to save her life.
但经历了第一次后  第二天再心脏病发作
But a second heart attack one day after the first
-她会死  -也许不会
- will kill her. - Maybe not.
抱歉打扰了  但...
I am so sorry to interrupt, but I...
我有个主意
I have an idea.
如果我们在她自杀之前先杀死她呢
What if we kill her before she kills herself?
我们会停止你的心脏
We'll stop your heart
在手术期间使用分流机代替
and put you on a bypass machine for the duration of the surgery.
如果你的心脏没有跳动
You can't have a heart attack
你就不会心脏病发作
if your heart's not beating to begin with.
解决了这台手术最大的危险
It takes the most significant danger off the table.
但血块不是仍会危及她的大脑吗
But aren't the clots a danger to her brain, as well?
这不能完全排除所有风险
This doesn't completely eliminate every risk,
但能解决最大的风险
but it does reduce the biggest one.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们明天一早就动手术
We'll do it first thing in the morning.
你修了我的水槽
You fixed my sink!
你知道现在几点吗
Do you know how to tell time?
你修了我的水槽
You fixed my sink!
不用客气  走开吧
You're welcome. Now go away.
那不在清单上
It was not on the list!
水龙头  不在清单上
The faucet. It was not on the list.
你不该碰的
You weren't supposed to touch it.
我把你吵醒我要修的东西都修好后
So after I fix everything you woke me up for,
我不怕麻烦地去修别的
then I go out of my way to fix something el--
它不在清单上是因为我已经修好了
It was not on the list because I'd already fixed it.
好吧  你没修好
Well, you fixed it wrong.
因为它还在滴水
Because it was still dripping.
我需要它滴水
I need it to drip.
保持和我在卡斯珀的水槽一样的频率
At the same rate as my sink in Casper.
之前滴得太慢了
It was too slow before.
现在我得重新修了
Now I have to fix it all over again.
这不公平
It's not fair.
我受够了
I'm done.
如果你不喜欢你的水龙头
If you don't like your faucet
或公寓里其他的设施  就搬走
or anything else in your apartment? Move.
你再在傍晚五点之后敲这扇门
If you knock on this door again after 5:00 p.m.,
我就打得你满地找牙
I'm gonna knock your teeth out.
BGM: Down In The Valley by The Head And The Heart
? I wish I was a slave to an age-old trade ?
? Like ridin' around on railcars and workin' long days ?
? Lord, have mercy on my rough and rowdy ways ?
? Call it one drink too many ?
? Call it pride of a man ?
? But it don't make no difference ?
? If you sit or you stand ?
? 'Cause they both end in trouble and start with a grin ?
? We do it over and over and over again ?
? I am on my way ?
? I am on my way back to where I started ?
? California ?
? Oklahoma ?
? And all of the places I ain't ever been to ?
? Down in the valley ?
? With whiskey rivers ?
? These are the places you will find me hidin' ?
? These are the places I will always go ?
? Theses are the places I will always go ?
-神经就像管子  -肖恩  这...
- Nerves are like pipes! - Shaun, th-- this --
我们得切断阴部神经以切除肌瘤
We need to sever the pudendal nerve to excise the myoma,
但如果我们再接合末端...
but if we reconnect the ends...
肿瘤的直径是四公分
The tumor is 4 centimeters in diameter.
这个要再接合末端的裂口太宽了
That's way too wide of a gap to reconnect the ends,
而且神经不会伸展
and nerves don't stretch.
我们不需要伸展它
We don't need to stretch it.
我们可以把阴部神经的末端
We can connect the distal end of the pudendal nerve
接到她大腿内侧的股皮神经分支
to the branch of the femoral cutaneous nerve from her inner thigh.
你宁愿失去大腿还是外阴部的知觉
Would you rather lose feeling in your thigh or genitals?
当然是大腿
Thigh, definitely.
他说得对吗
Is he right?
我们能那么做吗
Can we do that?
先讨论一下再通知患者
It probably would've been better to discuss this prior
会更加妥当
to meeting with the patient,
但没错  我觉得可行
but, yes, I think it could work.
切断缝合
Cut the suture.
嫁接神经已准备好  看看是否可行
Grafted nerve's in place. Let's see if it will conduct.
传导电极已准备好
Conduction electrodes are in position.
发送脉冲
Send a pulse.
再来
Again.
-再来  -好了  莫菲  我们知道了
- Again. - Okay, Murphy, we get it.
你的方法可行
Your idea worked.
你们俩都干得不错
Good job. Both of you.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thanks. - Thank you.
我猜梅伦德斯不常告诉你们
I'm guessing Melendez doesn't let you know this enough,
但你们俩都很棒
but you both are doing a great job.
如果你们需要什么  就算只是想聊聊
And if either of you needs anything, even just to talk,
我的门永远为你们敞开
my door's always open.
给我4-0薇乔
4-0 Vicryl.
好的  医生
Yes doctor.
4-0薇乔
4-0 Vicryl.
她已做好体外循环
She's on bypass.
阻断主动脉
Cross clamping the aorta.
准备好了吗
You ready?
-冲洗心脏  -冲洗中
- Flush the heart. - Flushing.
准备剖腹产
Let's prep her for C-section.
安德鲁斯医生
Dr. Andrews.
手术非常成功
The operation went perfectly.
但我下面没有感觉
But I don't feel anything down there.
你还处于麻醉状态  还需要...
You're still on the meds, so it's gonna --
知觉完全恢复需要半年至一年
It's going to take six months to a year to regain complete sensation.
你的大脑还需要时间搞清楚怎么回事
It'll take a while for your brain to figure out what we did.
但嫁接神经已经全部导通
But the grafted nerve is fully conducting.
你会好起来的
You're gonna be fine.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-能帮我个忙吗  -当然
- Can you do me a favor? - Sure.
-给我父母打电话  -好的
- Call my parents. - Absolutely.
-手术刀  -手术刀
- Knife. - Knife.
电刀
Bovie.
体外循环怎么样了
How're we on bypass?
-卡卢医生  你还在吗  -嗯
- Dr. Kalu, you still with us? - Yeah.
中心静脉压正常
Central venous pressure's good.
搭桥氧压200
Bypass oxygen tension's 200.
很好  修复胚胎骶骨
Good. Repairing the fetal sacrum.
要把胎儿放回母体了
Gonna put this baby back where it belongs.
「胎儿」
Baby?
你第一次没叫它「胚胎」
That's the first time you didn't call it a fetus.
只是个称呼
Just an expression.
我告诉过你
I told you.
是的  你说过了
Yes, you did.
你需要卧床休养四个月
You're gonna need to stay in bed for the next four months...
但你和你儿子的预诊都非常好
but both you and your son's prognosis is excellent.
我们想出生之后再确定性别的
We wanted it to be a surprise.
低级错误
Rookie mistake.
太好了
Yes!
我们今晚一定要庆祝
We are definitely celebrating tonight.
还睡什么觉  墨菲
Screw sleep, Murphy.
你得和我们一起去
You are coming with us.
你们要去哪儿
Where are you going?
-出去  我们要喝一杯  -我不渴
- Out. We're gonna drink. - I'm not thirsty.
别傻了
Don't be an idiot.
我的意思是...
I just meant...
来吧  兄弟
Come on, mate.
你刚拯救了一个18岁女孩的性生活
You just saved an 18-year-old girl's sex life.
而我救了两个人
And I saved two lives.
我们必须得喝
We are drinking.
来吧  肖恩
Come on, Shaun.
好吧
Okay.
太棒了
Cool.
BGM: There's Nothing Holdin' Me Back by Shawn Mendes
? Baby, there's nothing holdin' me back ?
? There's nothing holdin' me back ?
好了
All right.
我现在得回家了
I have to go home now.
? Just picture everybody naked ?
没事的  别担心
It'll be okay. Don't worry.
? She really doesn't have to wait ?
我们不会待太久
We won't stay long.
? Not really into hesitation ?
? Pulls me in enough to keep me guessing ?
肖恩
Hi, Shaun.
科琳
Hi, Colleen.
听说史蒂夫给你看了我爸的杂志
I heard Steve showed you my dad's magazine.
你喜欢吗
Did you like it?
别紧张  我不会告诉别人的
Don't worry. I'm not gonna tell anyone.
这没什么可害羞的
It's nothing to be embarrassed about.
所有男人都喜欢那种东西
All guys like that kind of stuff.
你想知道我的一个秘密吗
You want to know a secret about me?
我觉得你很可爱
I think you're really cute.
你有泡泡糖的味道
You smell like bubble gum.
我知道  是我唇彩的味道
I know. It's my lip gloss.
跟我来
Come here.
跟我来  小傻瓜
Come here, silly.
你觉得我好看吗
Do you think I'm pretty?
我也喜欢你
I like you, too.
如果你给我看  我就给你看
I'll show you mine if you show me yours.
来啊  我很好奇
Come on. I'm curious.
你也好奇吧
You must be curious.
我能亲你吗
Can I have a kiss?
我想知道那是什么感觉
I want to know what it feels like.
我可以亲你
I'll give you a kiss...
如果你让我看
if you show me.
看什么
Show you what?
你知道啊  把裤子脱下来
You know. Pull down your pants.
不
No.
来啊  肖恩
Come on, Shaun.
不  我得走了
No. I gotta go.
天啊  不敢相信你差点脱裤子了
Oh, my God. I can't believe you were about to pull it out.
不  我没有
No, I wasn't!
我怎么可能亲一个你这样的怪胎
And like I'd ever kiss a creepy weirdo like you.
别烦他  我们走
Leave him alone! Come on.
? Baby, there's nothing holdin me back ?
大家举杯  敬我们自己
All right, guys, a toast. To us.
因为我们太帅了
'Cause we rock.
无需多言
Nothing else need be said.
-干杯  -干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
? When you're with me, baby ?
? Baby, there's nothing holdin' me back ?